JONATHAN WHEATLEY

· Location: Rochester, MN 55904 · Phone: (218) 508-5600 · Email: jodawheatley@gmail.com · LinkedIn: in/jdwheatley

SUMMARY

REACT FULLSTACK DEVELOPER with 4 years of engineering experience optimizing systems and processes for usability and to maximize productivity across operations. Experience working across large data systems to ensure quality and accuracy in a highly regulated industry. Varied experience with data systems, designing and developing both frontend and backend components, including APIs and database management, integrating data tools, ensuring security and compliance, optimizing performance, and collaborating with various stakeholders to create data-driven applications and systems.

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

MAYO CLINIC
REACT FULL STACK DEVELOPER / SWE

ROCHESTER, MN

January 2023 - Present

Junior-level software developer supporting full stack development in an Agile environment for a unique project and innovative platform that utilizes generative AI for query-based analysis of medical scans, lab results, and patient demographics to predict/accelerate early detection, prognosis calculation, and medical treatment. Provide upgrades and maintenance with regards to system performance and technical issues for all distributed applications utilizing Object Oriented Design to enhance readability and reusability.

Developed reusable components with React utilizing Next.js to retrieve data from .Net backend API's; increased sprint velocity, code readability, troubleshooting, and implemented best practices for front-end web page development. Coordinated with design teams and project management to discuss application hierarchy, layout, and specifications

Development Environment: The application is built on C# and ASP.NET framework APIs, front-end web development through React, Node, JavaScript, and CSS. It is containerized with Docker and deployed through Google Cloud Platform (GCP). The SQL databases are accessed through Cloud SQL Proxy for testing and development while production level access is through Big Query. Oracle is leveraged for SSO and group/user policies and security. Developed and deployed code within google cloud environment.

- Utilized SAFe scrum practices to ensure adaptability and continuous delivery for a small pool of end-users and customers, with hundreds of thousands of projected users across the entirety of the Mayo health network
- Implemented automation best practices through ADO and Azure pipelines ensuring deliverable software provides business value and Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)
- Incorporated automated testing for development work with a focus on red-green refactor methodology
- Documented application use requirements, process, and testing with peer review and minimal constructive feedback, then trained 3 team members
- Coordinated with UI/UX team to make requisite changes incorporating user feedback and increased user satisfaction, overall functionality, and response time of application
- Increased data retrieval times and user display by 75%, increasing user satisfaction and usability; implemented C# code refactor (backend data) in the business logic level and at the data logic level

FEDERATED MUTUAL INSURANCE

OWATONNA. MN

December 2021 – January 2023

SYSTEMS DEVELOPER I

Supported the large-scale transition of legacy format legal documentation to new standards and ensured that document XML (utilized by IBM printers) was transformed accurately so as to reduce business downtime. Built a from scratch OutSystems SOAP API for the records purge and handled front-end and backend upgrades and maintenance of applications utilized for requesting legal forms be updated/changed.

Development Environment: OutSystems (React-based rapid prototype application development), Javascript, XML, XSLT, XPATH, .NET, Azure, Windows Virtual Machines

- Spearheaded upgrades across multiple Windows Virtual Machines using Oracle security measures, impacting multiple enterprise areas of business and 200+ users; utilized load balancing for ZERO service interruption
- Established OutSystems SOAP microservices designed to help with evaluating, assigning, and tagging records for purge compliance, allowing automation of purging records, reducing company liability and reducing storage load
- Executed SSIS and SSRS within OutSystems applications for data consistency, accuracy, and retrieval with MySQL
- Leveraged Bash scripting for automation of necessary software and security upgrades for Linux based systems
- ☐ Implemented software upgrades and transitions on Microsoft Virtual Servers through Oracle interaction to enhance load balance handling and leverage new software for business functionality
- Coordinated with team members to use Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to transition applications to the new database, requiring multiple application fixes, IaC file creations, testing, and data encryption; all achieved on time with no unscheduled downtime
- Leveraged Infrastructures as Code (IaC) best practices to enhance data parsing between SQL Server and Outsystems; reduced support debt (manual efforts) by 50%, created an uptick in software availability, and reduced deployment time to production
- Created an automated React-based API to purge targeted records based on legal requirements and eliminated 50,000+ out dated records on initial run with no unscheduled downtime
- Created XML templates which reduced transition time by 50% and reduced backlog
- Implemented fixes for database transition from DB2 to SQL Server, to meet compliance with new Forms Request Systems requirements; created new functionality for automated email notifications and automated daily database integrity checks for local database to SQL Server database and increased application efficacy, overall business value, and user satisfaction with no unscheduled down time

LEUKEN'S VILLAGE FOOD BEMIDJI, MN

PYTHON/JAVA APP DEVELOPER & LEAD PASTRY CHEF

June 2018 - October 2021

Provided significant time savings and business functionality enhancement to the bakery and led the greenfield development of a system that utilized python and simple string manipulation to pull from a database to simplify lists of unique ingredients for food products. Utilized Java and Maven to create a simplified, easy-to-use local desktop application which would print out a list of unique ingredients, how much the product cost the business to make, and how much the product should be priced at for sale. Technical Environment: Python, Java, Maven

- Directly managed a non-technical team of 5 who were also system users
- Utilized Python to create a new application that reduced time to create new product information and meet FDA compliance from a week to a matter of minutes; reduced costs by over 80%
- Updated application with Java and Maven to create a simplified UI, database, and additional functionality, thereby increasing application usability, business value, and further reducing product creation time from days to minutes
- Coordinated with upper management and software security to successfully deploy software to 3 locations within
 Minnesota, enabling each location to create new products with reduced downtime

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, 2021 – Bemidji State University

Master's Degree in Clinical Mental Health Counseling – Eastern Kentucky University

Bachelor's Degree in Psychology, 2016 – Berea College

TECHNICAL SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Full-Stack React • Next.js • Java • Java Script • C# • .Net • OutSystems • GCP • AWS • Azure DevOps • Instana • Bugzilla • Git • Vue • PowerShell • Python • SQL • GitBash • Java • Linux • Html5 • C++ • XQuery • XML • XSLT • Visual Basic • Maven • OpsGenie • Linux • Postman • Agile • PostgreSQL • Junit • CSS • Ajax • jQuery • Object Relational Mapping • Web Services • Jira • Data Visualizations • Infrastructure as Code (IaC) • REST APIs • Distributed Systems • Kubernetes • DevOps • XAML • SQL Server • REST API • Test Driven Development (TDD)